# Julian Podgórski

Warsaw, Poland

☐ +48 501 877 924 • ☐ j.podgorski@fastmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/j-podgorski

www.researchgate.net/profile/Julian-Podgorski/research

### About me

I am a geographer with 7 years of experience working with diverse geospatial, OSINT and cartographic data. During my career I have employed Python, QGIS and remote sensing methods to solve scientific problems. I am seeking a remote work position where I could develop my skills as a GIS specialsit and contribute to better understanding of the world around us.

### Skills

Data classification and image data processing with proprietary software and programatically. Good command of MS Word and PowerPoint, basics of MS Excel. Visualization of scientific data and mapmaking with Quantum GIS, GIMP, Inkscape, matplotlib. Internet research in open and scientific sources. Writing of scientific and popular-scientific texts. Typesetting with LaTeX.

GIS tools: Quantum GIS, eCognition, SAGA, Google Earth Engine, ENVI, PCI Geomatica, ArcGIS

**Programming:** Python (geospatial and image data analysis: GDAL, OGR, rasterio, pandas, opencv, geopandas, scikit-learn, jupyter), MATLAB

**Soft skills:** independence, determination, attention to detail, ability to work in international environments, ability to work remotely

### Languages

Polish: Native

**English**: Fluent in writing and speech; IELTS certificate

Swedish: Intermediate Good reading comprehension

Icelandic, Dutch, German: Basic A1

## **Professional Experience**

### Institute of Geophysics of Polish Academy of Sciences

Researcher/Primary Investigator

2016-2023

- Scientific and open-source research
- O Analysis of satellite imagery and other geospatial data (eCognition, Google Earth Engine, ENVI)
- O Data processing with use of MATLAB and Python (pandas, geopandas, scikit-learn)
- Writing and editing scientific articles (LaTeX)
- Creation of data visualizations and maps (Quantum GIS, matplotlib, Inkscape)
- O Technical and geographical interpretation of geospatial data
- O Four articles published in peer-reviewed scientific journals
- Winning and realization of PRELUDIUM grant from the National Science Centre of Poland
- O Participation in 8 international and Polish conferences

EDU-ARCTIC/EDU-ARCTIC 2/EDU-ARCTIC PL

Educator 2017-2022

- O Delivering remote educational seminars in English and Polish
- O Edition of entries for web-based educational dictionaries
- Preparation of educational videos
- Co-organisation of contests for children and youth

- O Several dozen lectures given on the topics of geography, geophysics and culture
- O Cooperation with Copernicus Science Center in Warsaw in creation of educational content
- O Participation in six educational events live as a lecturer or co-organizer.

### Courses and internships

SIOS Training course on Hyperspectral Remote Sensing

Remote specialist course: Polar remote sensing September 2021

Centro de Estudios Cientificos

Scientific internship, Valdivia, Chile

March-July 2020

Work with satellite imagery and topographical data, writing of a scientific article

SIOS training course on marine remote sensing in Svalbard

Specialist course: Marine remote sensing, Longyearbyen, Norway September 2019

**ESA Advanced Cryosphere Training Course** 

Specialist course: Polar remote sensing, Longyearbyen, Norway June 2018

Université du Québec à Trois-Rivières

Scientific internship, Trois-Rivières, Canada February 2018

Work with topographical data, independent work with MATLAB environment

De Gruyter Open

Remote internship February 2016

Data entry to a scientific journal database

### Education

#### Institute of Geophysics, PAS/University of Silesia

Ph.D. studies 2019-2023

International Environmental Doctoral School associated with the Centre for Polar Studies at the University of Silesia in Katowice

Institute of Geophysics, Polish Academy of Sciences

Ph.D. studies, Polar and Marine research 2016-2019

University of Warsaw

Master of Science, Geography, specialisation Remote Sensing and Cartography 2015-2017

Participation in student societies

O Student's Icelandic Club

O University of Warsaw Geoinformatics and Remote Sensing Students' Association

University of Stockholm

M.Sc., Geography, specialisation Glaciology and Polar Environments 2013-2015

University of Iceland

Student Exchange, NORDLYS programme exchange 2014

**University of Warsaw** 

Bachelor of Science, Geography, specialisation physical geography 2011-2013

Interests.....

International affairs Languages Nordic countries Scale modelling